劫梦惊魂
"限制级成人电影"
"挥之不去的记忆 无法抹灭"
"球赛之耻"
"缅因州戴瑞市"
"二十年前"
"我觉得心痛"
"因有一颗多愁善感的心"
"我总是感到孤独"
"因为我把爱全都留给你"
"省下一分一毛"
"史酷比狗狗  你在哪儿"
"我们要干活了"
"不全力以赴  就没乐趣"
"高林超市"
"我觉得心痛"
"因有一颗多愁善感的心"
"我总是感到孤独"
"因为我把爱全都留给你"
"高林超商"
"失踪女孩裘瑞肯郝尔"
"我们就来拯救你"
"太空飞鼠来了"
"闲闲无事  天天孵蛋"
"高林超商"
"戴瑞市"
"目标10394一20"
"奎宾蓄水厂3英哩"
"奎宾蓄水厂"
"婴儿的摇篮在树上"
"当风吹起时…"
"摇篮就会…"
卡尔汉堡店六块一个的汉堡  现在只卖三块九毛五
Carl's Jr. has this $6 burger, which really only costs $3.95...
真的很划算
...so you think you're getting some deal...
我觉得这是附近最好吃的汉堡
...but the truth is, it may be the best franchise burger out there.
昨天我吃了三个
I went there yesterday and ordered three.
天啊  快撑死了
By golly, those suckers almost filled me up.
回家后我又吃一整盒松饼
When I got home, I still had to have a box of Eggos...
并不是说卡尔汉堡无法满足我
...but that doesn't take away from Carl's achievement.
我是说  这个叫卡尔的家伙  一辈子活在汉堡的盛名之下
I mean, here's a guy who's got to go through life as Carl Junior, right?.
永远无法摆脱老爸的阴影  或卡尔的创始人  我猜的
Like he can never get out of the shadow of his dad, the original Carl, I guess.
你这样狂吃  不觉得会害死你老妈吗
Do you think this eating has to do with thinking you killed your mother?
想吃死来惩罚自己
That you're eating yourself to death as punishment?.
你认为是你杀了她  对吗  我可没那样说
You do think you killed her, right?. I never said that.
她在床上大声喊你
She called out to you from that big, fancy oak bed.
她说胸口疼痛  我从没跟你提过
She said she was having chest pain. I never told you any of that!
你怎么知道  她求你叫救护车
How could you know this?. She begged you to dial 91 1.
但她常常没事乱叫你  是不是  贝利
But she was always calling out for you, wasn't she, Barry?.
而你又不在场  怎么会知道
You weren't there. How could you know what happened?. How?.
那不重要  重要的是  别再责怪自己了
Doesn't matter. What matters is, you've got to stop blaming yourself.
否则  你真会吃死自己
If you don't, you'll eat yourself into an early grave for no reason.
你可以看穿我的脑袋  停
You're looking in my head! Stop it!
别看了  你不需这样
Don't look in there. You don't have to do it, Barry.
别管我
Leave me alone!
这不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
小琼
Jonesy?.
最近好吗  亨利
Hey, how are you doing, Henry?
你说什么
What's that you say?.
你聋了吗  我问你好不好
Are you going deaf? How are you doing?
你知道的  "天天孵蛋"
You know. SSDD.
可不是嘛
Well, yeah, of course.
这个周末有空的话   咱们去看看阿逹
Hey, you know, I was thinking if you were free this weekend we might go see Duddits.
好啊  我挺想他的
Yeah, absolutely. He's been on my mind a lot too.
很久没见到他了
It's been a long time.
进来
It's open!
不说了  有点事要处理  星期六见
I gotta go. I got a thing here. I'll see you Saturday.
好的
Yeah, right.
星期六见
See you Saturday.
我说  迪克先生
So, Mr. Defuniak...
我俩都是从缅因州来的
...do you know we're both escapees from Maine?.
你来自匹兹菲尔市
You're from Pittsfield.
你知道领奖学金的学生  作弊被抓到会怎么样吗
Do you know what happens to scholarship students caught cheating on exams?.
那天你不是感冒吗  大卫  你根本没来考试
You had the flu that day, didn't you, David?. You didn't take the exam?.
你因为生病没参加考试  就交个报告做为补偿
You missed the test. And since you were ill, why not write me an essay instead?.
用三千字描述诺曼底登陆的影响  马上去写
3000 words on the short-term results of the Norman Conquest.
是的  教授
Go get started. Yes, sir.
这比滚回老家好多了吧
Better to be from Pittsfield than go back to it.
谢谢  教授
Thank you, sir.
你怎么发现的  那天你根本不在
How did you know?. You weren't even there that day.
我就是有本事知道
Sometimes I just know.
你好
Hello.
这可能行不通
This probably won't work.
千万别小看卖汽车的  我们喜欢接受挑战  我是彼特
Never start that way with a car salesman. We love challenges. Pete Moore.
一个小时后  我要带人去看费莱堡的房子  很大一笔的佣金
In one hour I'm showing a house in Fryeburg. It's a big commission.
可是我弄丢了车钥匙  可以帮忙打一把吗
And I just lost my damn car keys. Could you possibly make me duplicates?.
这可要花一天的时间  天啊  我就知道
That takes at least a day. Oh, boy, I just knew it!
别紧张  崔希  或许我帮的上忙  我很会找东西的
Easy, Trish. Maybe I can help. I'm always good at finding things.
我有告诉你名字吗  我不记得  我猜的
Did I tell you my name?. I don't remember-- I guessed.
我们找钥匙吧
Now, let's find those keys.
嗨  瑞秋  嗨  彼特
Hey, Rachel. Hey, Pete.
看过了  我找不到  帮我想想
Miss, I looked again. I couldn't find them. Okay. I need your help.
当时你手上拿着咖啡  买了阿斯匹灵后
You had the coffee in your hand, bought aspirin...
走到车边才发现钥匙不见了
...went to your car, realized the keys were gone.
是不是这样  正确
That everything?. Yes.
这样问会有点奇怪  但可以帮助我思考
Look. This is gonna seem weird, but it's just a thing I do to help me think.
买阿斯匹灵前你买了糖果
You bought a candy bar before the aspirin.
巧克力棒
Mars bar.
是你的车吧
Yours, right?.
再问一个问题  我若找到钥匙  可以请你吃晚餐吗
One more question. If I find your keys, will you let me buy you dinner?.
西码头餐厅  六点半
West Wharf?. 6:30?.
那里有本州最好吃的蛤蜊  就在你回程的路上
Best fried clams in the state?. It's right on your way back.
好啊  没问题
Sure. Okay.
很好  太好了
That'd be nice. All right.
然后  你到这里  打开了包包
So you got here. You opened your purse.
咖啡  糖果和阿斯匹灵  全都乱成一堆
Coffee, candy and aspirin, you're juggling it all around.
就在这时候…
And that's when...
你把钥匙弄丢了
...you dropped your keys.
运气好让我给找到了
It's just luck, is all.
谢谢你
Thank you.
西码头餐厅六点半  知道了
West Wharf, right?. Half past six?. You got it.
又泡汤了
Another fuckarow.
我是琼斯  近来如何
Jones. How are you doing?
小毕"闲闲无事  天天孵蛋"  "闲来无事  天天孵蛋"
Hey, Beaver. Same shit, different day. Same shit, different day.
有事吗  没事  你要回家看老婆和小孩
Wanna talk?. No, you're trying to get home.
怎样真的  没什么事  回家吧
What's up?. Really, I got nothing. Go home.
小琼  干嘛
Wait, Jonesy?.Yeah, Beav?
小心点  小心什么
You be careful. Be careful of what?.
我知道就好了
Wish I knew.
"闲闲无事  天天孵蛋"
你说什么
What did you say?.
我什么也没说
I didn't say anything.
是啊  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
我的天啊
天啊
叫救护车  没救了
Somebody call an ambulance! lt won't do any good.
我稍不留神就听到撞击声  怎么会这样
I looked away for one second. Then I heard a thump. What happened?.
天啊  是琼斯教授
Oh, my God! Professor Jones!
我才和他碰面的  他不能死
I just saw him. He can't die!
让开
Clear!
没有用  没心跳  再试一次
No good. Flatline. Hit it again!
让开
Clear!
救得活吗  不乐观  我想没救了
What do you think?. I think it's no good. I think he's gone.
小心 "坏心" 先生
Watch out for lster Gay.
"六个月后"
别想搬那些
Jonesy, don't try to lift that stuff.
老毕  我先进去了  好的  待会见见
Beaver, I'm going in! All right, I'll see you in a second!
昨晚做爱了  那可好
Got blown last night. Good for you.
第一次吗  去你的
First time?. Bite my bag.
玩宾果时认识的  跟她回去后翻云覆雨
Met some lady at bingo, went back to her place, turned into a nice fuckaree.
这次没有败兴而归  那还用说
As opposed to a fuckarow. Obviously.
虽然勃起很好看  都很快从12点变到6点半
Though I've had perfectly good fuckarees turn into fuckarows in a flash.
试试看威而钢  威而钢
Try Viagra. Viagra?.
威而钢让我整天都一柱擎天
I'm practically at full salute all day.
这个叫做什么来着  久举症
I'm.... What do you call it?. Privatic?.
久硬症  亨利知道的
Prag-- Prasmatic?. Henry will know.
记得你小时候吧  你有久举的困扰吗
-You're thinking of fourth grade. -You're having wood problems?.
没吃过威而钢吧  去你的  当然没有
You haven't tried it, have you?. Hell, no!
吞下蓝色小药丸  就可以挺12个小时
Drop that little blue bomb, you're hard as a Louisville Slugger for 12 hours.
12个小时
Twelve hours?.
我是指像猛男一样  你不需要它来增加性趣
I'm talking Yastrzemski. You don't have to need it to love it.
宾果你刚说宾果  在教会地下室玩的那种
Bingo?. Did you say bingo, like the game in church basements?.
很多妞的那种  小毕
There's trim there. Beaver!
我真悲哀  没妞可泡
I thought my deal was pathetic.
你只管看着  不要插手  好吧
You just watch. That's your job. I'm fine.
亨利  最近是否更想阿达
H, you been thinking about Duddits more than usual?.
记不记得说好周末要去看他的
Remember we were gonna go see him that weekend?.
记得  然后我就被车撞了
I remember. Then I got hit.
跟你说件很奇怪的事
I gotta tell you something weird.
我被撞的那晚  站在路边  我看到阿达就在对街
The night I got hit, I was standing there and across the street, I saw Duddits.
就像第一次见到他的那样
Just like he was that day we first saw him back in Derry.
他大声求救  大家却视而不见
He was calling out for help and everyone was ignoring him.
然后他回头看我  直视着我
Then he looked over at me. He looked directly at me.
他要我过去
And he motioned for me to come to him.
你相信我看到他吧
You believe I saw him, don't you?.
当然  我相信
Yes, sir, I do.
阿达很爱我  我知道  他爱我们大家
Duddits loves me, I know that. He loves us all.
他宁死也不会伤害我们
He would die before he'd ever hurt us.
他为何把我叫到路上  让我被车撞
So why was he calling me into the street to get hit?.
可能还有很多事  我们并不了解
Maybe there's more to the story we don't get yet.
你知道个屁  说说看
You don't know shit. Name it!
可以  但我们得先打个赌
I'll name it after we come up with a small wager.
就赌50元吧  什么主题
50 bucks. What's the subject?.
电影里  大家一早起床
In the movies, when people wake up together...
就亲亲  搂抱和做爱
...they immediately start kissing and going at it.
他们都不用先起床  上个厕所或刷个牙
But they never get up first, take a leak and brush their goddamn teeth.
不只是我个人认为  每个人起床后都该先这样
Which is pretty much necessary when you wake up.
一直勃起不退叫做什么
What's it called when you got a constant woody?.
久硬症  看吧  我是有久硬症
You mean priapism. See?. I'm practically priasmic.
那叫持续勃起症
Priapismic.
管他的  反正就是很硬  你们就赌这个吗
Whatever! It's hard. That's what you're betting on?.
不是  我得说出哪部电影  符合现实生活
No, I can name the one movie where they acknowledge the scuzzy facts of life.
但是若没赌金  我赌两毛五  你赌两毛五  你赌50元
I'll give you a quarter. A quarter from you. 50 bucks from you.
"海誓山盟"   "海誓山盟"   没听过
Promised Land. Promised Land?. Never heard of it.
梅格莱恩和那个叫什么的
Meg Ryan and what's his name?. Reefer Sutherland.
李佛苏德兰 是基佛  1988年左右的电影
Kiefer. From, I don't know, 1988 or something?.
电影里  梅格莱恩起床便说  "猫跑到哪里去了"
So Meg Ryan wakes up in the morning and says, ""Where's the cat?. ""
然后他问 "什么猫啊"  她说"在我嘴里大便的猫"
And he says, ""What cat?. "" And she says, ""The cat that shit in my mouth.""
你输我50元
That will be 50 small.
胡扯  你瞎编的  他有本事捏造吗
Bullshit! You made it up. Could Beaver make that up?.
免费提供你们电影知识
You can have that priceless piece of cinematic trivia absolutely free.
这些资讯全记录在  "谁在乎" 记忆区中
I'm filing that in the ""Who-gives-a-shit"" section of my memory warehouse.
什么记忆区  你不记得什么是记忆区
What's the memory warehouse?. You don't remember?.
我忘了  你忘了记忆区
I must've forgot. You forgot?.
提示我就行了  别啰唆  就在脑袋里  我们每个人都有
Just remind me. Don't give me shit. It's in his head. We've all got one.
有被破坏过吗  还没有
Hasn't that place been condemned?. Not yet.
里面有太多东西了  新东西进来就得丢一些旧的
It's so crowded I have to throw something out every time I learn something new.
我买了手提电脑后  把歌词全放到电脑里
When I got my new laptop I had to throw out all my files of rock 'n' roll lyrics.
我的记忆区十年前被洪水冲走  没了
My warehouse was washed away in a flood about 10 years ago.
我不知道缅因州有那么多啤酒  居然可以造成水灾
I didn't know they had enough beer in Maine for a flood.
琼斯  如果这是你的真名…
Jonesy, if that really is your name...
你如何处理那些不用的档案   烧掉
what do you do with the discarded files?. I burn them.
你丢了"为你忧愁"的歌词  没有
You threw away the lyrics to ""Blue Bayou""?. No.
如果有无法忘怀的东西
No, if I really can't let go of something...
我脑中有一个私密办公室  我把所有秘密都藏在那里
...I sneak it back to an office where I keep my secret stuff.
你把阿达的记忆存在哪里
Where do you keep the stuff on Duddits?.
第三层全是他的专属记忆区
He's got a special section all his own on the third level.
最近老是想起阿达  你们呢  也是
I can't stop thinking about the Duds lately. How about you guys?.
就是这里  他老在这出没  即使他没真正来过
It's this place. He's all around here, even though he's never been here.
二十年来  再度光临森林小屋
This is our 20th year coming out here to Hole in the Wall.
妈的  已经二十几年了
And fuck me, Freddy, here's to 20 more.
二十几年
Twenty more.
敬阿达…
Here's to Duddits...
我们的捕梦人
...our dreamcatcher.
希望他在这里
Wish he was here.
敬阿达
To the Duds.
敬达格拉斯  敬阿达
To Douglas Cavell. To Duddits.
为何蒂娜珍的相片会出现   在崔氏企业的墙上
Why is Tina Schlossinger's pussy on the wall of Tracker Brothers?.
因为我说的  是张照片
Because I said so. It's a picture.
你看过吗  没有
Have you seen it?. No...
但坐我后面的小鬼见过
...but the kid who sits behind me in shop, he saw it.
崔氏企业早已是废墟
Tracker Brothers is deserted.
你不想看年度校花吗  那就别来
You don't want to see the homecoming queen's pussy?. Don't come.
这是小孩穿的
Fuck me, Freddy! Some kid's shirt.
那又怎样  还是新的
So?. It's new!
史酷比狗的图案
Scooby-Doo.
我属于达格拉斯卡威尔
""l belong to Douglas Cavell.""
如果我的主人不见了  请带他到戴瑞市枫树街19号
""lf the boy I belong to is lost, please bring him to 19 Maple Lane, Derry, Maine.""
这一定是启智学校学生的
Must belong to one of those kids from the Retard Academy.
快点  吃掉  吃完才可以走
Come on. Eat it. Eat it. Eat it and you can go.
嘿  住手
Hey, you guys! Quit it!
他妈的住手
Just fucking quit it!
你们在搞什么
What are you doing?.
你们逼他吃那个  你们有毛病啊
You're trying to make him eat that?. What's wrong with you?.
没错  你这个贱骨头
Got it. I'll make him eat this dog turd, then he can go.
我要他把狗粪吃完才放他走  要不要分一半
You go now. Unless you want half.
趁还来得及  快闪吧
Take a hike, girls, while you have the chance.
快滚  最后一次警告
Piss off. That's your final warning.
你给我小心点  怎么说
You better watch it! Why is that?.
我知道你是谁  我好怕喔
I know who you are. I'm trembling with fear.
你叫瑞奇  球队的四分卫  那怎么样
You're Richie Grenadeau, the quarterback! So?.
若把你干的好事说出去  别人想会怎样
What will people say when we tell them what we caught you doing?.
敢告诉任何人  你就死定了
You won't tell anybody anything because you'll be dead.
准备去昭告天下  彼特  就等你说  亨利
Get ready, Pete. Give the word, Henry.
彼特跑得超快  只要你们抓不到他就大功告成
Pete can fly. When you come for us, all we have to do is get in your way.
你想我会抓不到他吗
I can't catch that little dick?.
知道他是谁吗  彼特摩尔
You know who that is?. That's Pete Moore.
没错   飞毛腿彼特摩尔  没人能抓到他
That's right, fat-ass. Pete Moore. No one can catch him.
他会跑回家告诉他妈
He's going straight to his house to tell his mother.
他妈会通知警察  那就有好戏看
She'll call the cops and then we'll see.
你认识他  所以帮他  没见过
You know him, is that it?. Never saw him.
那干嘛找麻烦  因为这样被修理  值得吗  看看这白痴
Then why ask for trouble?. I mean, look at this moron!
他挺喜欢被整  你怎么知道他喜欢
He likes this attention. How do you know what he likes?.
你这浑蛋
Come on, you dickweeds!
想干架吗  没错
You want to fight us?. Yes! Yes!
我准备去宣传了  就等你下令
I'm gone, Henry. Just say the word.
何必呢  你们一定输的  因为这么做  是不对的
Why?. You'll lose! Why?.Because you can't do that! It's wrong!
我要告诉全世界每一个人
And I'm gonna tell the world! Tell everybody!
我们要离开吗  别让他们走  好好修理他们
You want us to leave, is that it?. No! Let's kick their asses!
我们走吧  以后再找他算帐  懂吧
Let's go. We'll get him later. You know that.
以后再找你们算帐
Get you all later.
没事了  可以停了
It's okay. You can stop now.
想想办法  各位
Do something. Somebody!
我有办法了
If I do...
但是你们敢泄漏出去  以后就别当朋友了
...and you tell anybody, I'll never hang with you guys again.
我从不知道小毕会唱歌
I never knew Beav could sing.
唱得真好  不要闹了  别笑我
Beaver, that's beautiful. I mean it. Not one word.
小毕
Eaver!
你已经有个歌迷了
You've got a fan.
这是你的吗
This yours?.
达格拉斯卡威尔  是你的名字吗  是啊
Douglas Cavell. That's your name, right?.
我是阿达
I Duddits.
你说什么  我是阿达
What?. I Duddits!
你是阿达   阿达
Duddits?. Duddits.
来吧  我们送你回去
Duddits, we got to get you home.
你们过来  把他留在那里
Hey, guys! Come here! Leave the kid there.
站在那  跟史酷比一起在这里
Stand right here, Duddits. Right here with Scooby, okay?.
我的天  什么玩意
Jesus Christ bananas!
不可能是蒂娜珍吧
No way is that Tina Jean Schlossinger.
大概是她祖母吧
Maybe her grandmother. Good going, Beav.
大老远跑来就为这个
Holy God. We came all the way here just for that?.
不是的  是为他来的
No. We came for him.
彼特  你忘了热狗
Hey, Pete. You forgot the dogs.
天气要变坏了  两个暴风雪要来  从亚伯塔区开始  会有约8寸高的积雪
Weather moving in. Double storm. Alberta Clipper first, maybe eight inches...
之后  东北方又会来另一个
...with a nor'easter on its tail.
快回到木屋里去  正要回去  高先生
Get on back to the cabin, Henry. Heading straight there, Mr. G.
别在耽搁了  不会的
Don't mess around. No, sir.
慢慢来  老兄
Easy, fella.
慢慢来  没事吧  你是对的
Easy. You're okay. You're all right.
谢天谢地
Thank God. Thank God.
Gee, thank God!
我昨天在树林里迷了路
I'm lost. I've been lost in the woods since yesterday.
进屋去吧  会暖和些
Let's get you inside. Get you warm.
怎么会迷了路  就是嘛
How would that be?. Sure.
我帮你脱
Here, let me get that.
瑞克麦卡西  盖瑞琼斯  大家都叫我小琼
Rick McCarthy. Gary Jones. But it's Jonesy to everybody.
我们的手机坏了  无法打电话求救
Our damn cell phones are on the blink now, so I can't call for help...
但是车子会马上回来
...but our car will be back soon.
没想到我会获救  我和同伴走失了
I didn't think I'd make it. I lost the folks I was with.
被你救了  真是命大
You saved me, that's for sure.
那是什么
What's that?.
捕梦网
It's a dreamcatcher.
印地安的灵物  赶走恶梦用的
Indian charm. Catches nightmares...
让你在这里很安全
...keeps them away. Keeps you safe down here.
我的恶梦够多了
I've had enough nightmares.
我整晚一直在打嗝
Been doing that all night.
我之前吃了些梅子
I ate some berries in the dark.
大概梅子搞的鬼
I think they must have upset me.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
一大早就喝酒  应该是有毛病  但我只有在这里才这样
Anyone who drinks at 11 a.m. needs to take the cure, but I only do it here.
平常  下午之前我滴酒不沾
In the real world, I never drink till after 5:00...
要是沾一滴  从此戒酒
...and if it ever does, I'm on the wagon for life.
很高兴听你这么说
Glad to hear it.
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?.
大约六个月前   小琼被车撞的那天
About six months ago, the day Jonesy got hit...
我对一个病人做了很可怕的事  我羞辱他  还把他赶出办公室
...I did something terrible with a patient. Humiliated him. Drove him out of the office.
他叫贝利纽曼
Barry Neiman.
几天前  在报上看到他的消息  他吃太多而撑死
Couple days ago, I saw his picture in the paper. He ate himself to death.
我可不用这个故事来卖车
Mind if I don't use that story next time I'm trying to sell a Mustang?.
那个胖子吃死自己前  你一直都挺丧志的
Henry, you were a lead balloon long before this porker munched his way to eternity.
谢啦  你还真善解人意  太令人感动了
Thanks. You're a real comfort. You got a real delicate touch to you.
吃点东西吧  老兄  有助恢复体力
Here you go, Rick, buddy. That will fix you up.
天啊  天气又要变坏了
Jesus Christ bananas! Some fuckarow this is turning into!
谢啦  我想该有的都有了
Thanks a lot, Pete. Yeah, I think I got it all.
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?.
乔克雷敦  叫我小毕就行了
Hi. Joe Clarendon. Call me Beaver.
瑞克在林中度过了恐怖的夜晚
Rick here had a bad night in the woods.
欢迎
Welcome.
冻伤的吗  吃花生酱引起的过敏
ls that frostbite?. No, I get the same thing from peanuts.
这是过敏
It's allergy.
谁要起司三明治
Grilled cheese, anyone?.
汤就行了  谢谢  我要  端出来
No, the soup's fine for me, thanks. I'll bite. Sail it over here.
我妈常喂我青豆汤  当我…
My mother used to feed me pea soup when I was feeling--
我的老天
Bitch in a buzz saw!
有史以来最大的打嗝声  世界冠军
I've heard some mighty burps in my time, but that's the blue ribbon.
真不好意思
I am so embarrassed.
瑞克在林中吃了些莓子
Rick ate some berries in the woods.
天啊
Oh, my God!
天啊  真恶心
Oh, my God, that's awful!
真是抱歉
I'm so sorry!
别担心  至少比闷在里面舒服
Rick, buddy, don't worry about it. There's more room out than in, anyway.
你到底吃了什么  猪粪吗
What have you been eating, woodchuck turds?.
我觉得…
Know what I think?.
你需要躺下  小憩一下
I think you need to lie down and take you a little nap.
有道理
You know, I bet you're right.
大概是太累了
I'm just tired, that's all.
去睡吧 我的帽子
Come on. My hat.
小毕
Beaver?.
在这里
In here.
谢谢收留我  谢谢你们两位
Thank you for taking me in. Thank you both.
任何人都会这样做的  也许会  也许不会
Shit, anybody would have. Maybe. Maybe not.
想吐的话这可用这个
All right, this is in case you have to urk...
厕所在左边第三间
...if you can't get to the bathroom, which is the third door to your left.
别走错第一间  在里头便便
If you go in the first, you'll take a shit in the closet.
有任何需要  我们就在外面
If you need anything, we're outside.
天啊  真臭  我需要新鲜空气
Fuck me, give me some air!
有防毒面具吗  这里需要清洁大队
We got any gas masks handy?. We need a biohazard team in here.
想不想听听更可怕的事  不太想
Wanna hear what will freak you out more?. Not really.
你看到他的肚子很大吗
You know his huge stomach?.
他来的时候是正常的  但胸部很凸出
When he got here, his stomach was normal, but his chest was out to here!
亨利在就好了
I wish Henry was here.
他是心理医生  不是内科医生
He's a shrink, not an internist.
他读过医学院  你呢
He went to med school. Did you?.
我曾经考虑过…
I thought about it.
你最好开快一点
You better get a run at it.
妈的  小心
Shit! Watch it!
我的天呀
What the hell?.
你没事吧  我的腿断了  唉呀  我的腿
Pete, are you okay?. No, I broke my leg! Man, my damn leg!
好的  忍耐一下
Okay. Hang on. Hang on a second.
卡住了  我不能  天啊
I'm caught! I can't--God!
天啊  亨利  过来帮我一下
God. Henry! A little help here!
等等
Hang on, Pete. Hang on.
我帮你解开安全带  我才刚开了啤酒
Okay. Here comes the seat belt. I just opened that beer.
我扶你
I got you.
腿如何
How's your leg?.
没断  只是不能动
Well, it ain't broken. It's just locked up, is all.
他该不会受到辐射污染吧
You don't suppose he got exposed to radiation?.
我在电影里看过  电影中的那家伙后来头都秃了
I saw that once in a movie. Guy ended up bald as Telly what's-his-fuck.
这个家伙头发很多  可是他的红疹越来越大
This guy's got plenty of hair. But that red mark got bigger while I was watching it.
你这是在干嘛  花生酱可以让我镇静下来
What are you doing?. Peanut butter calms me down.
其他人还要吃呢  我会留一些
Somebody else might want to use that jar. I'll leave some.
小毕
Beav.
Beaver.
干嘛大惊小怪
Criminettlies!
我觉得是个女的
I think it's a woman.
我先告诉你  待会过去  我一定掐死这婊子
I ought to warn you. I'm gonna strangle this broad.
我想她死了  我才不管
I'd guess she's already dead. I'll strangle her anyway.
她差点害死我们
She almost got us both killed.
哈罗  我们来了  别害怕
Hello! Here we come, ma'am. Don't be startled.
哈罗
Hello?.
算了  她死了
Forget it, H. She's gone.
哈罗
Hello!
听得到我说话吗  你没事吧  听得到我说话吗
Ma'am, can you hear me?. Are you okay?. Can you hear me?.
我想这里都是这样打招呼的
I wonder if maybe that's how they say hello around here.
这位小姐  你差点害死我们
Listen, Miss Road Kill, you almost got us dead.
出点声啊
Say something.
我必须找到瑞克
I have to find Rick.
好的  瑞克
Okay. Rick.
我的老天爷
Fuck me, Freddy.
那些动物身上的红疹  就像瑞克脸上的
What's all that red stuff on their fur?. Just like McCarthy's cheek.
从来没见过这样的情形  连熊看起来都很害怕
I never saw anything like this before. Even the bears look scared.
他们要去哪里  我倒不担心他们逃去哪里
Of what?. Where are they going?. It's not where that worries me...
而是他们为什么要逃离
...it's what are they running away from?.
搞什么
What the hell?.
太好了  他们可以送瑞克去医院
This could be perfect. They can get Stinky to a hospital.
各位
Hey, you guys!
我们需要帮忙  我们这里有个病号  这个区域暂时被隔离
We need some help! Got a sick guy inside! This area is under temporary quarantine.
留在原地别动  什么隔离
Stay where you are. What quarantine?.
我们这里有个病人  我们需要协助
We got a sick guy down here! We need your help here!
有个家伙病的很重  先把他送走吧
We got a real sick guy here! Take him with you now!
还好你们没事  我们会在24至48小时内  把状况处理好
Glad you're okay. This situation will be resolved in 24 to 48 hours.
去你妈的
Kiss my bender!
我得问清楚  老兄  因为我实在很混淆
I gotta ask you, old buddy. Because I'm confused.
这是 "闲闲无事  天天孵蛋"   当然不是
ls this SSDD or not?. Definitely not.
今天的事可新鲜了
Different shit today, Pete.
而且是相当怪异  如果你想知道
And a pretty weird day so far, if you want to know.
过来到这里
Over here.
小心
There you go.
慢点
Easy.
小木屋距这里有九英哩  我想应该没问题
It's nine miles to Hole in the Wall. I think I can manage it.
我去把雪车开来接你们
I'll bring the snowmobile back and get you both.
彼特  听我的话  不要回车上拿啤酒
Now, Pete, you listen to me. Don't go back to the car for beer.
陪着她  别让她冻着  我发誓绝不会  戴医师
Stay with her. Keep her warm. Right hand to God, Dr. D.
亨利
Henry!
万一你还没回来我们就死了
If we die before you get back...
你保证让大伙知道  她不是我的妞
...promise you'll tell everybody she wasn't my date.
告诉你  小琼  我真受不了这样
I'm telling you, Jonesy, I don't like this at all.
真是屋漏偏逢连夜雨  倒楣透顶
This is turning into a double fuckarow. A real jobba-nobba.
瑞克  还好吧  有点不舒服
Rick, you okay?. I'm a little sick, fellas.
想清一清肠胃  瑞克  开门啊
I just need to make a little room. McCarthy, Rick, open up, man.
走开  再不开我们就冲进去了
Go away! Open the door or we break it down.
我不能有点隐私吗  你哪边流血了吗
Can't a man have some privacy?. Rick, where are you bleeding from?.
流血  我没有流血
Bleeding?. I'm not bleeding.
把门撞开  我不知道该不该进去
Let's do it. I'm not positive I wanna go in there.
万一他快死了怎么办   "史酷比狗狗  准备干活了"
What if he's dying?. Scooby-Dooby-Doo, we got some work to do now.
我数到三  准备好了没
On three. Ready?.
一   二
One.... Two....
等等   如果撞不开
Hold it! What if we just bounce off?.
不全力以赴  就没乐趣  没错  这样才有乐趣
No bounce, no play. Right. No bounce, no play.
一
One....
二   三
And a two.... Three!
天啊  我的妈
Oh, fuck! Oh, man! Fuck!
我不想看这个  我不敢看
I don't want to see this! I can't see this.
闭嘴  先生  他还活着吗
Shut up a minute. Mr. McCarthy?. Rick?. ls he still alive?.
不知道  瑞克
I don't know. Rick?. Rick, are you--?.
还能拉屎  应该还活着
Oh, man! Jonesy, if he can still do that, he must be alive.
听得见吗  我想他死了
Can you hear me?. I think he's dead.
胡扯  他刚刚还拉了屎  听得见
Bullshit! He dropped a clinker! I heard it.
那不是拉屎  太过分了  快回答我
I don't think that was a clinker. That's enough, snap out of it!
天啊
Oh, my God! My God!
不  不
No! No?.
干得好  把它困住了  除了化粪池它别无去处
Good move! It's trapped. Got nowhere to go but the septic tank.
妈的
Oh, shit!
听着  小毕  我们要换手  什么
Listen, Beaver, we're gonna change places. What?.
你去储藏室   我才不要
One of us is gonna go to the shed. No way!
闭嘴听好  那里面有胶带
Shut up and listen! There's friction tape there.
去拿来  我们把盖子封死
You go get it, come back. We'll tape the lid down.
这样我们就可逃出去
Then we're gonna get the hell out of here!
你去拿胶带  别逞英雄
You get the tape, Jonesy. Don't be brave, Beav.
你跑的比我快  我会压住盖子
You're faster than me. I'll sit on Thumper.
不要  万一它跑出来  你无法光用屁股对付它
No, if it does get out, you can't fight it. Not with your hip.
天啊  快去
Oh, my God! Goddamn it! Go!
可是  小毕
And Beav?. Yeah?.
坐稳了  兄弟
Sit tight, buddy.
没事的
Okay.
行了
All right. Okay.
该死  马桶战士琼斯  回答我  小琼
Shit! Earth to Jonesy! Come in, Jonesy!
小琼  小琼
Jonesy. Jonesy.
我要镇静
Calm down now. Okay.
好了
Okay.
好了  就差一点
Okay, here it is. Okay.
快找胶带
Find the damn tape!
在哪里
Where is it?.
我来了
Coming, Beav!
小毕  小毕
Beaver! Beav!
我找到   天啊
I got the-- What the--
小琼  快离开
Jonesy, get out of here!
小毕
Beaver.
快走  把门关上  不
Get out! Shut the door! No.
快跑  小琼
Run, Jonesy.
你把他杀了
You killed him.
你杀死小毕
You killed Beaver.
你把他杀了  你这王八蛋
You killed him, you fuck!
你想干嘛
What do you want?.
他把那红疹叫 "莉普蕾"   是"异形"女主角的名字
The men call the red stuff Ripley, after the broad in the Alien movies.
我们会消灭  从隔离区逃出的动物
We eradicate the animals as they flee the Blue Zone.
那居民呢
And the populace?.
会把他们带到高林超商  直到想出解决方法才放人
We're bringing civilians to Gosselin's. We'll detain them till we figure this out.
对付外星人的事就交给你  就这么办  伙伴
And Owen?. This time the ETs belong to you. That's right, bucko.
你就是蓝色精英部队的队长  终于等到了
You'll be Blue Boy leader. Finally.
还剩几个  大约一百个
How many left?. About a hundred.
数量不致造成威胁
Yeah. Not nearly enough for a serious incursion.
我猜是因太空船坠落造成的
My guess is, it's a crash-landing.
他们不会在这样的地形  或气候中降落
They've never picked terrain like this before. Or cold weather.
您的指示
What's your call?.
让他们逃出隔离区就麻烦了
The biggest threat is them getting out of our net.
不管是不是意外坠机
Crash-landing or not...
他们会想办法逃出来   散播病毒 "隔离区"
...they'll try to get out and spread the infection.
我就说他们绝不会无缘无故来  除非是想占领这世界
I always say they never visited a world they wouldn't rather own.
老技俩
They're up to their old tricks.
装成普通人的模样
Using a standard grayboy look...
有着一对天真无邪的眼睛  像婴儿般光滑的皮肤
...with the innocent doggy eyes and smooth baby-butt skin.
他们呈现出人类的样子
They project what they think we want to see.
但我看过他们的真面目  你绝对不会想把妹妹嫁给他
But I've had a look at the real thing. You wouldn't want it marrying your sister.
"莉普蕾"有不同的看法  真的谁有意见
Difference of opinion about the Ripley. Really?. Who has an opinion?.
你想会是谁呢  麦迪森将军
Who do you think?. General Matheson.
三星上将麦迪森  三星
Three-star General Matheson. Three?.
你什么时候见过他  昨天他们召我去问话
When did you see him?. They called me in yesterday.
那些家伙能有什么的意见
What's the opinion of those enlightened cocksuckers...
他们根本就没接触过外星人
...who've never been near an ET?.
不是所有受害都会长红疹  有些人没有长
They say the fungus doesn't take hold in all victims. Some of them get over it.
真的吗  那么那些怪物呢
Really?. And what about the shit weasels?.
那些从屁眼拉出怪物的人呢
The ones blasting out the basement door?.
麦迪森该不是认为  那些人已经康复了
Does Matheson think folks get over one of those puppies?.
他们认为只有少数受感染的人  会散布病毒  不是所有人
Their theory is, they'll only grow in a small percentage of the exposed population.
你同意那个论调吗
Do you like that theory, bucko?.
我想那是胡扯
I think it's crap.
你有办法掌控
So if you thought someone had been exposed...
和外星怪物接触过的人  我不准他们在外面游荡
...and you had them in your grasp-- I wouldn't want them walking out...
看来我们的想法是一样的
...to wander as they wish. Bucko, I think we're on the same page.
志同道合
Pissing in the same latrine.
万一 "莉普蕾" 从林区中逃出
If the Ripley gets out of this pine-tree paradise....
绝对不允许这种情形发生
Well, it just can't be allowed to do that.
我已隔离了整个区域
I've quarantined the entire area.
任何人插翅也难飞  知道了  老大
Nothing leaves alive. Roger that, boss.
进来
Come!
梅普带来了  长官
Got Maples here, boss.
我是下士梅普  长官  我知道你是谁  梅普
Corporal Maples, sir. I mean, boss. I know who you are, Maples.
蓝色精英的每一成员  都是我亲自挑选出来的  有时候我也怀疑自己的判断力
I handpicked every man in Blue Boy group. Sometimes I wonder about my judgment.
是的  老大  对不起  是长官  你清楚蓝色精英的信仰吗
Yes, sir. I'm sorry, boss. Do you know the Blue Unit catechism?.
清楚  长官  是全队伙伴信念一致  蓝色精英是陆军的一部分吗
Yes, the B.U.C. for all buckos. ls Blue Unit part of regular Army?.
不是  是更优秀的  蓝色精英如何运作
No, boss. Better. How does Blue Unit operate?.
秘密行动时  我们互不相认  也不显示阶级  我们没有老大  我们是独立的个体
Under the radar. We do not salute, display rank, say ""sir."" A force unto ourselves.
一般军队和蓝色精英相比  逊毙了
Regular Army compared to Blue Unit?. Pussies.
我们根据什么法则运作  战斗法则
Under what rules does Blue Unit operate?. Rules of combat.
这就对了  小伙子
That's right, laddie.
一个士兵若不遵守上级指令  会使所有人身处于险境
When a soldier disobeys a superior's orders, he puts everyone at risk.
他会被上级立刻处分
And is to be punished immediately by appropriate command personnel.
那就是我
That's me. Capisce? Good.
回答我一个问题  你就可以滚了
Now answer me one question and you can boogie out of here.
但你必须老实回答
But you have to answer honestly.
今早六点你站岗时  在14号蓝色隔离区
You were on containment detail at 06:00 this morning, sector 14 of Blue Zone.
是否准许一个女人  带着她的四岁女儿
Did you allow a young woman and her 4-year-old daughter...
开着车离开蓝色隔离区
...to exit the zone in their own vehicle on Hickam Valley Road?.
克提斯上校  她从未到过禁区
Colonel Curtis, she hadn't been in the zone.
她只是开错方向  绝不是被隔离的人
She made a wrong turn. She couldn't have been contaminated.
这是实际发生  还是她告诉你的
You know this for a fact?. Or because she told you so
实际发生  长官  你敢以童军名誉发誓
For a fact, boss. Scout's honor
你敢发誓告诉我  你说的是有事实根据
Can you raise your hand and tell me honestly that you know this for a fact?
那就发誓  梅普
Then do it, Maples.
发誓吧  以童军名誉
Swear on it. Scout's honor.
以童军名誉
Scout's honor.
别鬼叫了  小子
Stop your blatting, laddie-buck!
你刚逃过一次军事审判
You just avoided a court-martial, boy.
你如果敢再欺骗我  就准备万箭穿心吧
You lie to me again, you'll be facing a firing squad.
趁我还没改变心意前  把他带走  让他离开这里
Get him out before I change my mind. Let's get him out of here.
哨兵
Sentry!
天啊  亚伯  我警告过他
Jesus, Abe. I warned him.
他算是逃过一劫
Could have gotten off with a slap on the wrist.
你毁了他的手  他跨越了我定下的界限
lnstead of taking his whole hand?. He crossed the Curtis line!
竟敢在我的地盘撒谎
He came into my house, told me lies.
他当我是疯子啊  是有点疯
You think I'm crazy, Owen?. A little.
我是发了火  但那小子太糟糕了
I lost my temper there. But that little worm did something worse.
竟让那个女人离开
The pretty mom he let pass this morning?.
目前她在谷仓里  被 "莉普蕾" 缠上了
She's down at the barn right now crawling with the Ripley.
二十五年了
Twenty-five years, Owen.
二十五年来都在对抗  那些外来的混帐东西
Twenty-five years I've been going out to fight these alien bastards...
我要让他们知道  他们挑错地方  敲错门了
...show them they picked the wrong place, knocked on the wrong fucking door.
老实说  小伙子  我有点倦了
And frankly, laddie, the tank is running a little low.
幸好  在这复杂险境中  还有让人高兴的事
Luckily for me, there's one bit of good news in this blizzard of bullshit.
我有接班人  今天你来带队攻击  明天由你接管我的工作
I have you. To lead the assault today and to take over for me tomorrow.
你在说些什么  这是我最后一次任务
What are you talking about, Abe?. It's my last dance, Owen.
从现在起  就由你来带头
From now on, you will lead the band.
知道这是哪弄来的吧   约翰韦恩送的
You know where I got that?. John Wayne.
没错  他给我的  现在我把它送给你
That's right. He gave it to me. And now I'm giving it to you.
我不知该说什么  别感情用事了  伙伴
Abe, I don't know how to....Let's not get all girlie with each other.
只要告诉我该怎么执行任务  攻击要迅速猛烈
Just tell me how we do it. We go in fast and hard.
如何脱身  全身而退
How do we come out?. Clean...
而且面带微笑
...and smiling.
亲爱的  我回来了
Honey, I'm home.
这样也不错  小眯一下
That's a good idea. Catch a little shuteye.
才有元气放屁
Save your energy for those horrendous farts!
你真会甜言蜜语  我觉得你也很有魅力
Well, it's very nice of you to say so. I find you very attractive also.
你是少数会开  福特货车的女人
You're one of those rare women who can handle the full-size Ford Expedition.
而且能把货车当轿车开  就像一辆高级豪华大轿车
The truck that handles like a luxury car. A really big luxury car.
但  老实说  有件事我想提一下
But seriously, folks, there is one issue I'd like to bring up...
以防万一我死在这里
...just in case I should, you know, kick the bucket out here...
变成彼特冰封僵尸  那并不是不可能的
...turn into a goddamn Petesicle. Not that I think that's inevitable.
我相信亨利  小琼或小毕  很快就会来救我们
I'm sure Henry or Jonesy or Beaver will be coming to get us soon.
他们都是我的朋友  是我最要好的朋友
They're my friends. We're all best friends.
小姐  恕我直言
Now, ma'am, I'll be very candid with you about this...
所以拜托  别吓到  或把我当成怪胎
...so please, don't get freaked out or think that I'm some kind of weirdo...
或拒绝跟我晚餐约会
...who you shouldn't meet for the best fried clams in Maine.
即使只是吃个单纯的晚餐
Just some innocent fried clams at the West Wharf!
我们这四个好朋友
You see, the four of us, best friends...
有个共同的朋友叫阿达
...we all have this other friend by the name of Duddits.
这个朋友阿达  并不是你想像的普通朋友
And our friend Duddits, well, he's not your average old buddy.
很久以前  有一天  他送我们每人一个礼物
One day, a long time ago, he gave us all this kind of gift.
这礼物  该怎么说呢
It's this.... How shall I put it?.
是一种特异功能
This ability. This ability to know things...
我们有看透事情的能力  不需透过言语就能彼此交谈  就像心电感应
...to talk to each other without talking at all, just mind-to-mind.
知道我在说什么吗
Do you see what I'm getting at?.
我就知道你会了解
I knew you would.
最近我常做一个梦
Lately, I've been having this dream...
梦里  我明白阿达  为何能把这样的能力传给我们
...and in the dream, I understand how Duddits could give us a gift like that.
我觉得阿达不是地球人
I think maybe our friend Duds is not from this planet.
他是从其他星球来的
I think Duddits is from somewhere else...
他来协助我们  对抗某些东西
...and he came here to prepare us for something.
是不是有点疯狂
It's crazy.
跟你谈论一个世间仅有的完人
Talking shit about the only perfect person I ever knew.
他太完美了  真不敢相信他是人类
He's so goddamned good. I can't believe he's a human.
我应该赞扬他  而不是质疑  他来自哪个银河系
I should be singing his praises, not questioning what galaxy he's--
我想小便
I gotta pee.
先去解决吧
That's what I should be doing.
敬你  阿达
Here's to you, Duds.
人类的完美杰作
The highest civilian decoration.
上帝  我再也不喝酒了
Lord, I will never drink again.
我把话说明白
Let me get this straight.
昨天你要退出  宣告放弃  不再留恋
Yesterday you want to call it quits, throw in the towel, pull the plug, curtains.
今天你却苦苦哀求祷告  再几小时  再几英哩
Today, you're begging, praying. Couple more hours. Couple more miles.
快下决定
Make up your mind.
小琼  行了  混蛋
Jonesy! Way to go, motherfucker!
"拯救世界的任务"
Here you come to save the day!
"太空飞鼠来了"
搞什么
What the hell?.
"外星" 人是谁
Who's Mr. Gray?.
你想告诉我什么  小琼
What are you trying to tell me, Jonesy?.
你不是小琼
You're not Jonesy.
搞什么  琼斯先生  我们刚刚路过了什么
What was that, Mr. Jones?. What did we just pass on the road?.
你在跟我说话吗  是啊  是跟你说话  琼斯  还是该叫小琼呢
Are you speaking to me? Yes, I am, Mr. Jones. Or is it Jonesy?.
你的朋友都这样叫你吧  交个朋友吧
That's what your friends call you, isn't it?. Let's be friends.
为何让我活下来  我要借用你的身体
Why are you letting me live? I'm borrowing you.
我们去兜一兜风  小毕从未伤害过任何人  你却把他杀了
We're going to take a little journey. Beaver never hurt a soul and you killed him.
他没什么大脑  我在你这里找到有用的东西
He had nothing in his head. I've found something useful in yours.
去你的  我知道那是什么意思
Fuck you! I know what that expression means.
我研究过你的脏话记忆区
I've studied the foul language section of your memory warehouse.
老实说  不怎么样  这个如何 "外星"人  吃屎吧
Rather distasteful, I must say. How about this, Mr. Gray?. Eat shit and die.
为何叫我 "外星"人
Why did you call me Mr. Gray?.
小心 "坏心"(外星)人
Watch out for lster Gay.
有人跟你提过我  是谁告诉你的
Someone told you about me. Who told you about me?.
想知道的话  自己解读
If you want to know, why don't you read my mind?.
你居然能对我隐藏心思
Surprisingly, you're able to keep things from me...
我不懂  但很快就会找到答案
...I don't understand it. But I'm sure I'll figure it out soon.
彼特  天啊
Oh, Pete, Jesus!
那妖怪想咬断我老二
Motherfucker tried to bite my dick off, Jonesy.
我以为只有我前妻会这样
I always thought it would be my ex-wife did that.
我带你去看医生
Let's get you to some help.
还分的清路吗
Can you still see the line, buddy?.
没路我也到的了高林超商  我知道  但是
I don't need the line to get to Gosselin's. No, I know that, but...
我们不去高林超商  你能带我上95号公路
...if we didn't want to go to Gosselin's, how would you get us out to 95?.
95号  谁管去哪里  我很痛
95?. Who gives a shit?. I'm hurting here, Jonesy.
怎么了
What's wrong with you?.
你并不是  住嘴  你伤得太重了
Wait a minute, you're not-- Shut up, Pete.
不知道自己在胡说些什么
You're too messed up to know what you're saying.
为时已晚  彼特  我要你立刻上车
Too late for that. Pete, I need you to get onto the snowmobile right now.
你他妈的是谁  说话口气很像007
Who the fuck are you?. You sound like one of those James Bonds!
这一定和大鳗鱼有关  你该不会是…
This has to do with the fucking eel, doesn't it?. You're not--
住手  我会说服他帮忙  告诉他怎么走
Stop it! I'll get him to help. Pete, tell him what he wants to know.
怎么上95号公路  我得去麻州
Now, Pete, which way to l-95?. I need to go to Massachusetts.
这是特异功能
My, my. That is a gift.
谁教你的
Who taught you that?.
以后得靠你帮忙了
You're gonna be a big help, Pete.
坐上来
Climb aboard.
表演结束了  老兄  让我进去
Show's over out there, buddy. Let me in. Let me in.
里面到底有什么
What have you got in that part of your mind, professor?.
你的记忆资料都在这里吧
Your memories are out here in the warehouse, aren't they?.
是谁叫你防着我  又是谁教彼特那些技俩
I want to know who warned you about me. And who taught Pete that nifty trick?.
我相信答案就在这里  我会花点时间找到答案的
I'm sure the answers are here. It'll just take me a while to find them.
找到答案  让我进来吧
To find them. Think about letting me in.
这样才有礼貌
It's the polite thing to do. Polite thing to do.
小毕
Beav!
这是什么玩意
What is this?.
小毕
Beav.
他妈的
Shit!
怎么会这样
Fuck me, Freddy.
妈的
Asshole!
再见  小毕  我爱你  兄弟
So long, Beav. Love you, man.
我们把它做成了艺术品
We all made them in art.
我先做完的  送了一个给阿达
I finished first, so I made one for you, Duds.
我做错了  想不起来线要怎么接
Mine's deformed. I couldn't figure out the string.
毕佛  亨利  琼斯  彼特  没错  好家伙
Eaver, Henny, Ownzy, Eet! That's right, my man.
是我阿达
I Duddits.
是的  我是阿达  我是阿达
Yes. I Duddits. I Duddits!
我是阿达
I Duddits!
阿达会找到她的
Duds will find her. How?.
阿达无所不能  她是启智学校的
He can do anything. She's from the Retard Academy.
总是爱挥着手  我们得救这女孩
She always waves. We've gotta save this girl.
救 "地球"  不是"地球"  是个女孩
Save this world?. Not the world, Duds. A girl.
以后再去拯救地球  "坏心"人
We'll save the world some other time. lster Gay?.
是啊  很离奇  你要帮我们
Yeah, it's a mystery. We need you to solve it.
捕梦人  阿达能读我们的心思  又来了
Dreamcatcher. Duds'll read our minds. Not this again.
住嘴  我们得想想裘丝的处境
Shut up. We gotta think of Josie.
裘丝…
Josie, Josie, Josie.
裘丝瑞肯赫尔
""Josie Rinkenhauer.""
裘丝  没错  你能找到她吗
Josie?. That's right. Can you find Josie?.
"这简直太疯狂了"  再说一次
This is completely crazy. You can say that again.
我什么都没说  "有  你有说  我听到了"
I didn't say anything. You did. I heard you.
"你说  这简直太疯狂了"  我可没那样说
You said, "This is completely crazy "I didn ' t say that.
我只是想想而已
I thought it.
去你的  只有阿达会读心术  我们可没这本事
Kiss my bender. Duds can hear people's thoughts. We can't.
"你确定吗  小毕"
Are you sure of that, Beav?
大伙  裘丝一定在这里
Hey, guys! She's down here for sure!
裘丝  你在里面吗
Josie, you down there?.
裘丝
Josie! Josie!
她一定在下面
Fuck me, Freddy, she's down there.
我知道  我脑袋有她的影像
I know it. I can see her in my head.
我也是
Yeah. Me too.
救命  拜托
Help! Please!
救救我  忍耐一下  我们来了
Help me. Hold on, Josie, we're coming!
裘丝  撑着点
Josie, hang in there!
别唱了  她已经够害怕了
Don't sing. She's scared enough.
闭嘴  这里有老鼠屎的味道  抓住我的脚
Shut up. There's like rat shit in here. Hold on to my feet!
小毕  看到什么了没有
Pete, do you see anything?
阿达  我们救到她了  救了裘丝
Duds! We got her! Here's Josie.
蓝色精英队长  情况如何  兄弟
Blue Boy leader. How we doing, bucko?.
没问题  老大  迅速利落  果然是蓝色精英本色
Right here, boss. Fast and hard. Wouldn't have it any other way, Blue Boy.
长官
Sir?.
我看见了
I see it.
请不要伤害我们  你们不会受感染的
Don't hurt us. We're dying.
那是哪来的声音  不是从无线电发出来的
There is no infection here. Whose radio is that?.
他们把声音  直接传到我们脑里
It's not the radio. They're putting it into our heads.
我们非常无助  没错  各位
We are helpless. There it is, gentlemen.
直接传入我们脑中
There's no infection here. Directly into our heads.
这样你们明白  我们在对抗什么样的敌人
This gives you an idea what we're up against.
你们是不是纳闷  为什么那些可怜的家伙
If anybody's thinking, Those poor, helpless little folk...
会裸着身体  不带武器  在坠毁的太空船边
...all naked and unarmed beside their crashed intergalactic Winnebago...
是什么冷血怪物…
...what kind of a dog, what kind of a monster...
即使听了他们无助的告白  也无动于衷
...could hear that heartbreak and go in just the same?
我就是那冷血怪物  我们非常无助  就快死了
Well, I'm that dog. I'm that monster. We are helpless. We are dying.
他们像披着羊皮的狼
These mothers are as harmless as a fox in a henhouse.
而我就是来对付这些狼  听懂我在说什么吗
And I'm here to kick some ass! Are you with me?.
是的  老大  听到了
Yes, boss! Roger that, boss.
老大说的是
Right on, boss.
请不要伤害我们
Don't hurt us.
我看到了
I have a visual.
天啊
Holy shit!
妈啊  真壮观
Damn, look at the size of that.
蓝色精英  这是队长  目标接近  进入4级备战状态
Blue Boy group, this is Blue Boy leader. Target imminent. Move to level 4 readiness.
兄弟们  锁定目标  准备发射
Gentlemen, lock and load.
飞弹就绪
Hellfires are hot.
发令攻击  欧文
Sing it out, Owen!
蓝色精英  这是队长  我们要扫遍整片林子  把那些废物清除掉
Blue Boy group, this is Blue Boy leader. Clean up the forest and get rid of this trash!
别伤害我们  拜托  别伤害我们
Don't hurt us. Please, don't hurt us.
我们不具传染性  我们很无助且濒临死亡
There is no infection here. We are helpless.
全力射击  开火
Fire at will! Fire!
叫他们撒走
Owen, get them out of there!
快爆炸了
It's gonna blow!
蓝色精英  立刻撒退  重复  停止攻击  撒退
Blue Boy group, withdraw at once. I repeat, cease firing and back off!
差一点就能全部歼灭  这是自动引爆
We can get them! It's self-destructing. Back off!
赶快撒离  我们就在敌人上方
Blue Boy group, get out of there! We're on top of it!
欧文  撒离
Owen, pull out now!
撒离  快离开  正在撒
Pull out! Get out of there! Pull out!
琼斯  我一直想起我们的朋友  "史酷比"小子
Jonesy, I've been thinking about our friend. Our Scooby-Doo buddy.
我早就认为  他是来向我们预警某些事情的
For a long time I thought he was sent to us to warn us about something.
但一直不知道是什么事  别谈他的事了
I could never figure what it was. Don't talk about him.
直到今天我才了解  当前所发生的事
Not till today. It was this, right now.
就是他要警告的  彼特  说说你那朋友吧
He wanted to warn us. Go ahead, Pete. Tell me about your friend.
是他教你那些漂亮的把戏  不是  琼斯说的没错
Did he show you that nifty trick?. No. Jonesy's right.
来吧  彼特  我们来谈谈嘛  操你妈  王八蛋
Come on, Pete. Let's talk. Bite my bag, motherfucker!
好啊  我也会操  我操你全家
All right, Pete, I'll bite. Your bag and everything else.
不  你这混蛋
No, no! You bastard! No!
彼特
Pete.
别跟他说话  快走
Don't talk to him! Get out of there!
怎么样  老兄  谢天谢地你来了  长官
What's up?. Thank God you came by, governor.
我的车坏了  人生了无生趣
I'm broke down here and fearing for my life.
这只狗真漂亮
That's a good-looking dog.
你们去哪里   高林超商
Where you headed?. Gosselin's.
你会去那附近吗
Any chance you're going near there?.
我正要去那里
That's where I'm going.
你后车门好像开着
Well, I believe your tailgate has come open.
我检查一下
Let's take a look.
我看你是要运货到蓝色基地
I see you have some cargo you're taking to Blue Base.
我有好东西给你吃
Got a treat for you, lke.
吃到饱  吃那红色的东西
All you can eat. Eat all the red stuff.
好狗狗  乖狗狗
Good doggy. Yes. Good boy.
吃多一点  好吃好吃
Have your fill. Tasty, tasty.
想吃多少就吃多少
Eat all you want--
小琼  你要干嘛
Jonesy. What are you up to?.
琼斯
Jonesy!
天啊
Oh, God!
别动  否则开枪了  不准离开隔离区
Halt or we'll fire! You cannot leave the quarantine zone!
别动   我已经不动了
Halt! I think I just about halted here.
跟我来  欧文
Come with me, Owen.
让你看些东西  可是你一定不会想看
I'll show you things you'll wish you'd never seen.
我们要在这待多久  就快结束了
How long we gotta be here?. lt'll be all right.
我要见我的律师  他们一定有什么
I demand to see my lawyer! There must be something they can do.
不要担心  会好起来的
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
我们什么时候可离开  几小时内吧
When do we get out?. Within hours.
在美国境内  你不可以这样拘留人  我叫你待在这里
You can't do this to people in America! I told you to stay over there!
这是我老婆  政府会不惜一切代价
My wife-- Government's doing everything they can...
救你们出去  我们会竭尽所能
...to get you out of here. Please don't worry. It's all right.
保障你们安全无虑
We're doing everything to make sure you're safe.
几个小时内  就能把你们送回家
We'll get you back to your homes within hours.
没感染
All clear.
有事吗  先生  叫什么名字
Can I help you, sir?. What's your name?.
亨利  亨利戴夫林医生  是医生  太好了
Henry. Dr. Henry Devlin. A doctor?. Good.
我们这里需要医生
We need doctors in there.
来吧  老弟  我们喝一杯
Come on, laddie, I'll buy you a cup.
先生  你从哪来的  波士顿
You, sir, where you from?. Boston.
波士顿  很棒的城市  我们很快就会送你回去
Beantown?. Great city. We'll have you back there in no time.
大概明早以前
Maybe by morning.
快点
Hurry up, bucko.
你看到小孩脸上的东西吗
You see that crud on the faces of children...
你知道我为什么喜欢乡下  因为乡下才能这么干
...you know why I relish a turn in the country like we had today.
你表现的很好  我感到非常骄傲
You were excellent out there, O. It made me feel very proud to--
亚伯  你还好吗
Abe?  Abe, you okay?
亚伯
Abe?
我很好  对于这种任务  我可能太老了
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine. I must be getting too old for this shit.
不知道怎么回事
I don't know what the hell that was about.
我别无选择
It's the only way, Owen.
我们必须隔离消毒整个地区
We've got to cauterize the site.
他们全都得死
They've all got to die.
只能这样
It's the only way.
我们还不确定他们是否被感染
But we don't know that.
研究报告指出  受感染的人极有可能复原
The studies point to the strong possibility of recovery for many exposed subjects.
那些研究报告可靠吗  这不就是答案
The studies show squat, that's what they show.
过去25年工作  如果是由三星上将麦迪森执行
If Matheson had been in my spot for the last quarter-century...
你根本活不到现在
...you'd have never made it to your first jerk-off.
那些灰着脸的外星浑蛋  早就把你们当午餐吃了
Those gray bastards would have had you for lunch back in Armpit, Kentucky.
有些人已经好多了  至少一半的人  几天内就会康复
Some get better. At least half will be over it in a few days--
谁好了呢  泰瑞莎修女
Which ones, Mother Teresa?.
你敢保证   他们不会把传染病带回家
Can you guarantee they won't take it home like a present for the family?.
我告诉你该担心什么   该注意什么
I'll tell you what you should be worried about. What should be on your mind.
不是这些少数的不幸事件
Not these few unfortunates.
而是该担心的那些  搭便车的外星浑蛋
What you should be worried about is a hitchhiker.
你说什么  搭便车
What?  A hitchhiker.
我们最害怕的是这些浑蛋会藉着
Our greatest fear is that a grayboy would catch a ride...
人的身体离开这里而不被发现
...with somebody and would carry them out of here, without being consumed.
也会藉着人类散布病毒   就像散播种子般
To scatter the infection, like Johnny-fucking-Appleseed.
你确定没有这样的人逃走  没有
Are you sure there isn't such a person?. No.
即使有  也插翅难飞
But I am sure that if there is one he won't get out.
况且我们在隔离区  布下了天罗地网
Not with the net my boys put up around the Blue Zone.
能不能歼灭所有受感染的人
And if we do a thorough job on the ones we've got.
能不能不要太感情用事  尤其我们的任务  是在保护整个地球
If we don't get gooey about the little picture when our job is taking care of the big one.
懂吗
Capisce?
你若觉得这对我来说很容易  那你就大错特错
Owen, if you think this is easy for me, you're crazier than my mother was.
那些可怜的家伙
Those poor schmucks.
开着雪佛兰的车子  在便宜的商店购物
They drive Chevrolets, shop at Wal-Mart...
从不错过 "六人行" 影集
...never miss an episode of Friends.
他们是一般的平民百姓
These are Americans.
射杀同胞…
The idea of slaughtering Americans...
让我倒尽胃口
...it just turns my stomach.
但我仍得执行  因为不做不行
But I'll do it. I'll do it because it needs to be done.
凌晨2点开始行动  2点半就能结束  之后什么都不用烦了
So if we start at 2, we can be done by 2:30. And it's all behind us.
剩下的只是梦魇
Except for the dreams.
对啊   除了梦魇
Yeah, except for them.
你要怎么跟老婆说  你的所作所为
What are you gonna tell Rita about what you did here?
如果你女儿问起  你要怎么跟她说
What are you gonna tell Katrina when she's old enough to ask?
你认识我吗  我不记得何时见过面  但你认识我
You know me, don't you?. I don't remember when we met, but you know me.
我们别浪费时间了  我直接了当告诉你吧  你有两个难题
We don't have time to screw around. You've got two problems.
一个你很清楚  一个你并不知道  继续说
One you know about, one you don't. Go ahead.
你的师父克提斯上校  追捕外星人25年  已经疯了
Your mentor, Colonel Curtis, he's gone insane from hunting aliens for 25 years.
如今要你帮他  滥杀几百个无辜的百姓
Now he wants you to help him kill hundreds of innocent people.
你是谁  我
Who are you?  Me?
这个待会再讨论   我们先离开此地
Talk about that later, once we get out of here.
我可以预测你的想法  欧文
You're predictable. You won't let me burn on this fence...
你不会让我被这栅栏电死的  你更不会帮克提斯滥杀无辜
...any more than you'll help Curtis kill those people.
你现在心里想的是  袋子里的卫星数位无线电
What you're thinking now is whether that digital sat-scan transmitter...
是否能联络到某人
...in your duffle bag will let you get through to somebody.
一个叫麦迪森将军的人
Somebody named General Matheson.
"有时我们必须杀人"  "但真正的目的是去救人"
"Sometimes we have to kill, but our real job is to save lives."
你爸爸是个很棒的军人
Your father was a great soldier.
这是他生前的最后一句话
Those were his last words.
你一直带着他的相片
You carry his picture with you always.
把真相告诉我
Tell me everything.
你会救这些人
You'll save these people.
我们一谈完  快用无线电连络麦迪森…
When we're done talking, get on the transmitter, contact Matheson.
大队人马会到达
Cavalry rides in.
第二个难题来了
That takes care of problem number one. Now comes the hard part.
你真以为封锁了感染途径  没有所谓搭便车的外星人
You think the infection's been contained, that there's no hitchhiker.
你错了  我最好的朋友已经被上身
You're wrong. He's riding with my best friend on Earth.
他叫盖瑞琼斯  他已经不是他了
A guy named Gary Jones. And he's out there.
如果不马上逮到他  我就快感应不到他了
You and I don't get after him right away, he'll get out of my range...
到时地球的麻烦可大了
...and some kind of shit is gonna hit the planetary fan.
我们的梦魇
Our nightmare hitchhiker.
所以那密医要一张通行证  好去抓他朋友
And all Dr. Mystery wants is a free pass so he can catch his friend.
说的容易  不是我相信他  你该听听他的说词
Very convenient. I'm saying you ought to hear his story.
好啊  他人在哪
Okay. Where is he?
我让人把他带到车库
Had him taken to the tractor shed.
好吧  我会和他谈谈  再和你对质
Okay. I'll check him out and we can compare notes.
悉听尊便  老大
Whatever you say, boss.
快点  别再浪费时间了
Come on, come on. Time's a-wasting.
好了  士兵  开门
All right, lad, open up.
波士顿来的医生
Dr. Boston?.
你在里面吗
Are you in here?.
我在这里
I'm here.
我还能在哪里呀
Where I've been put.
竟在自己家里当起囚犯
A prisoner on my own damn property.
走吧
Let's go!
快点  走吧
Come on, let's go.
上车
Get in!
你差点撞到我了
You almost ran me down.
我以为会你感应到我
Figured you'd read my mind and get out of the way.
蓝色精英部队  原地不动  你们要听从陆军的指挥
Blue Unit, stand down. You are under regular Army command.
立刻放下武器
Put down your weapons at once.
你们的任务已经取消了
Your mission is rescinded.
蓝色精英任务已经不存在了
This is no longer a Blue Unit operation.
放下武器  重复一次  放下武器
Put down your arms. Repeat, put down your arms.
一切听从麦迪森将军的指令
General Matheson has assumed command.
很好  欧文
Okay, Owen.
很好
Okay.
你刚越过了我的界限
You just drove over the Curtis line.
去哪  南方
Where we going?. South.
目前唯一知道的  只要接近琼斯
All I know right now. Just get me in range of Jonesy...
就可以知道一切真相
...we'll know everything we need to know.
那支枪有来头  借看一下
That's some gun. Can I have a look?.
你用这枪  很炫  别人送的
Kind of flashy for a guy like you, isn't it? It's a gift.
我知道
I know.
你到底在哪里  小琼
Where are you, Jonesy?
拿起电话  打亨利专线给我
Pick up the phone. Call 1 -800-HENRY.
喂  小琼吗
Hello? Jonesy!
天啊  我就知道是你  他把你带到哪去了
Jesus Christ, I knew it was you. Where's he taking you?
麻萨诸塞州吗  是吗
Massachusetts? He is?
阿达吗  好的  我会来救你  你撑着点  小琼
Duddits? Okay, I will. You hang in there, Jonesy.
小琼
Jonesy?
他断线了
He hung up.
把枪还给我
Give me back my gun.
我们得去戴瑞市  他们要去那里吗
We gotta go to Derry. That where they're going?
不  他们要前往麻州  我们需要阿达的协助
No, they're going towards Massachusetts. We need Duddits.
小琼说外星人很怕阿达
Jonesy says Mr. Gray is afraid of Duddits.
你兄弟和外星人纠缠这么久  还撑的下去吗
Your buddy, he's still alive after all this time with Mr. Gray?
还可以  他有免疫  我想是因为他已经死过一次了
Yeah, he's immune. I think it's because he died.
他被车撞了  心跳停了两次
He got hit by a car and his heart stopped. Twice.
可能连他自己都不知道
I don't think he even knows it.
他死而复生  一定改变了什么
He came back from the dead. Must have changed him somehow.
似乎阿达知道这一切  是不是这样呢
It's almost like Duddits saw this whole thing coming. Is that it?.
小琼告诉我  是阿达让他发生车祸的
Jonesy told me it was Duddits who drew him into the accident.
如果我们抓到他  必须杀了他
If we catch him, we're gonna have to kill him.
你知道我们必须杀他吧  唯有杀了他才能阻止外星人
You know we have to do it. It's the only way to stop Mr. Gray...
但也得先抓着他
...assuming we can catch him.
上一次看到阿达是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Duddits?.
很久了
Long time ago.
好多年了
Years.
你为何那么确定他帮得上忙
What makes you so sure he can help?.
阿达很行的
Duddits can do anything.
我不清楚为什么  但我想他无所不能
I didn't understand that then, but I think it's always been true.
就是他把我们搞成这样子
He's the one who made us like this.
哪样子  你知道  很灵异
Like what? You know, weird.
他等你很久了
He's been waiting for you.
被暴风雪耽误了
Blizzard slowed us up.
亨利…
Henny, Henny.
亨利
Henny.
好想你  亨利
I miss you, Henny.
好想你
I miss you.
亨利
Henny.
好久不见了  亨利
Long time, Henny.
天啊  达太太  他怎么了  得了白血病
My God, Roberta, what is it?. Lymphocytic leukemia.
我会让你把他带走  但我必须告诉你原因
I'm gonna let you take him, but I have to tell you why.
他准备好了  知道你来
Just now, when he was getting ready...
他变得很兴奋
...Henry he was so excited.
他已经很久没这样了
Like he hasn't been in such a long time.
我想
I think...
他若和你一起  也许可以快乐些离开
...that if he's with you, he might die happy...
而不必孤单地死在这里
...instead of in this awful room.
记的帮他把外套扣紧  他耐不住寒冷的
Be sure the parka stays on tight. Cold devastates him.
药物及服用方法都在这
The medication and instructions are in here.
再见  妈
Bye, Mom.
再见  阿达  要乖乖的
Goodbye, Duddie. Be a good boy.
去拯救世界吧
Now, go save the world.
不用担心  阿兵哥
I'm all right, laddie.
他们还没那个胆抢走我的地盘  没那个胆
They haven't got enough courage to take my trailer. Not yet, anyway.
情况如何
What've we got?
他们正离开戴瑞市  从95号公路南行  前往麻州
They're leaving Derry, Maine, heading south on 95. Toward Massachusetts.
麻州
Massachusetts?
继续追踪
Stay with it, bucko.
麦迪森将军  请进
General Matheson. Come in, please.
太好了  亚伯
This is very nice, Abe.
历经艰难终于回来了
Been home through some rough times.
我们还有什么没讨论的
Was there something we hadn't covered?
我想我不用跟你说   我非常佩服你之前的成就
I don't think I got to say before how much I respect the work you've done.
我真的好后侮
It was with sincere regret--
郝曼  可以这样叫你吗
Herman-- May I call you Herman?.
策略上  我们无法达成共识  但我们都同意这样解决
We may not agree on all the strategic initiatives, but we do agree on this:
我老了  没力气了  是该退休了  就这样
I'm past it. Burned out. Just needed a push, that's all.
蒙他拿那次灾难后  就该退休了
Should have quit after that mess in Montana.
我甚至无法相信自己的判断力
Even I don't trust my judgment anymore.
所以
Oh, yeah....
我的技术人员告诉我  这里仍有电子通讯设备在使用
My techies tell me we're getting some electronics reading hot from in here.
是的  我一直在用卫星电话  和我太太连络
Yes, I've been talking to the wife on my sat phone.
不知道你有没有见过芭芭拉  她一直希望我退休
I don't know if you've ever met Barbara. She's been after me for years to retire.
我敢说她现在一定乐透了  一小时内将会关闭所有器材
She's very happy, I can tell you that. I'll have everything shut down in an hour.
这样可以吗
If that's soon enough.
没问题的
That will be fine.
怎么关掉这烂灯
How do you turn off the goddamn lights?
或许你不该那么快  就干掉那些警察
Maybe you shouldn't have been so fast to kill that trooper.
把地球当成自己家了
You're making yourself at home.
你懂个屁  告诉我  喜不喜欢这声音
You have no idea, Jonesy. Tell me how you like this:
"或许你不该那么快"  "就干掉那些警察"  不赖吧
"Maybe you shouldn't have been so fast to kill that trooper." Not bad?
不喜欢啊  外星人
Oh, don't like that, Gary, do you?
小琼  他在警车里面
Ownzy. He's in a police car now.
他在警车里
He's in a police car now.
可以看到他们在哪吗
Can you see where they are, Duds?
小琼   "坏心" 人在他身体里
Ownzy. He's in lster Gay.
"坏心"人
Mr. Gray.
没错  阿达 "坏心" 人在他身体里
That's right, Duds, he is in Mr. Gray.
"坏心"人   就是"外星"人
"lster Gay"  is Mr. Gray.
我们得救这女孩
We gotta save this girl.
救 "地球"
Save the world?
不是"地球"  是女孩  以后再去拯救地球
Not the world, Duds, a girl. We'll save the world some other time.
"坏心"人
Ister Gay?
你早就知道了
You already knew.
他要去哪里  阿达
Where's he going, Duds?
外星人要把小琼带到哪
Where is Mr. Gray taking Jonesy?
"坏心"人要 "睡"
Ister Gay, he want war.
睡觉  不是睡觉  是水
War?  Not war, water.
外星人要水
Mr. Gray wants water.
我知道他要去哪儿
I know where he's going.
他要去奎宾蓄水厂  什么奎宾蓄水厂
He's going to the Quabbin Reservoir. What's Quabbin?
它提供全波士顿的饮用水
It supplies drinking water for all of Boston.
什么
What?
一条虫毁世界
One worm kills the world.
One worm kills the world?.
天啊   一条虫
Oh, my God. One worm.
回到小木屋时  看一堆虫破卵而出
Back at our cabin, I saw the worms that come out of these weasels.
外星人一定是  要把虫子弄到水里
Mr. Gray must want to get one into the Boston drinking supply.
一条小虫能使全世界受感染
Just one worm infects the whole world?
这样走没错吗  是的
Are we going right?. Yes.
走495号往麻斯公路  干的好  伙伴
Take the 495 to the Mass Pike. It's not far. You're doing great, buddy.
准备更困难的挑战吗  交给你一样任务
Now, are you ready to try something hard?. I want to ask you something hard.
好啊  亨利
Yes, Henny.
太好了  你能和小琼说话吗
Good. Can you talk to Jonesy?
有办法让他感应到你吗
Can you make him hear you?
小琼
Ownzy...
还有 "坏心"人
...and lster Gay.
阿达
Duddits.
我就知道  他一直都在这里
I knew it. I knew it. He's been here all along.
等待机会
Waiting.
小琼  看来我们不是偶遇
Jonesy?. It appears we didn't meet by accident.
我们都亏欠朋友  阿达
We owe it to our friend, Duddits.
我不懂你说什么  不懂  不是吧
I don't know what you mean. No? Maybe not.
或许你那精明的朋友  不想让你知道他的来历
Maybe your clever friend didn't want you to know what he was up to.
那就是为什么  你的记忆库里  没有我的资料
That's why you had nothing in the warehouse about me.
阿达并不想告诉你  他想为你做什么
Duddits didn't bother to tell you what job he had in mind for you.
这都不重要
It doesn't matter.
他的计谋失败了  不是吗  狗狗不
His little scheme didn't work. Did it, lke? No, no.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
记忆库中有什么诗词可用的
What was it your poetry file had to say?
"沉睡前  还有誓言要承诺"  "路途依旧遥远"
I have promises to keep And miles to go before I sleep
"沉睡前  路途依旧遥远"
And miles to go before I sleep
阻止那辆直升机
Stop that chopper!
加速  老兄  别那么龟毛
Punch it, dude. Don 't be a pussy.
谢谢提醒  外星小琼
Thank you, Gary Jones.
到水池上方
Go up around the reservoir.
波士顿的导管从12区开始
Aqueduct to Boston starts in Shaft 12.
耐心点  小子
Patience, bambino.
就在前头
Just up ahead.
留在这照顾你的朋友
Stay here and take care of your friend.
不管听到什么都别离开
No matter what you hear.
再见了  医生
So long, doctor.
乖狗狗  要听话
Good doggy.
好女孩
Good girl.
妈的
Shit!
你这个王八蛋
You son of a bitch!
等等
Wait.
回到车里  阿达
Go back to car, Duddie.
那里比较安全
You'll be safer there.
小心  小琼
Look out, Jonesy.
我就知道你会来
I knew you'd come, Henry.
你不会让我死的
I knew you wouldn't let me die.
你到底是谁
Who the fuck are you?
你不认识我吗  不认识
Don't you know me, H?I don't know.
我必须杀了你
I think I'm gonna have to shoot you.
才能确定是不是你
Just to be sure.
你说得对  老兄
Well, maybe you're right, my friend.
我自己也不确定  是否外星人还在体内
I don't know myself if Mr. Gray is gone.
他有可能还藏在里面
He could be hiding in here somewhere...
等待良机
...waiting for his chance.
说些他不知道的事
Tell me something Mr. Gray couldn't possibly know.
讲些只有我们才知道的事
Tell me something only we would know.
"闲闲没事  天天孵蛋"
SSDD.
这不够
Not good enough.
你问我吧  随便你问
Well, you decide. Ask me anything.
在崔氏企业那里  我们认识阿达的那天
At Tracker Brothers, day we met Duddits...
墙上写了什么字
...what was painted on the wall by the window?.
"不…"
No...
"全力以赴"
...bounce....
"就没乐趣"
No play.
哈罗
Hello...
"坏心"人
...Ister Gay.
你
You.
"史酷比狗狗"
Ooby-Ooby-Doo...
"我们要干活了"
...we got some work to do now.
"坏心"人
Ister Gay...
走开
...go away.
不要
No!
我是阿达
I Duddits.
亨利
H?.
小琼
Jonesy.
如果琼斯是你的真名
Jonesy, if that really is your name....
那你就输我50元  胡扯
That'll be 50 small. Bullshit.
我是阿达  我是阿达
I Duddits. I Duddits.
他们都是我朋友  是我最要好的朋友
They're my friends. We're all best friends.
敬阿达  我们的捕梦人
Here's to Duddits, our dreamcatcher.
字幕制作 Ocr：多啦A梦 校对：昊天 审查：残飞鸟